OK.
So now, our regularization goal here
is to maximize the distance that the margin boundaries are
from the decision boundaries.
This will be our regularization type, OK?
Now, we can proceed to define the objective function itself
for finding large margin decision boundaries.
It has two components, as we've already seen.
It has a loss.
And it has a regularization.
We have talked about both.
So let's quantify, now, what that loss actually is.
We know that the linear prediction here, the sine of
ed relates to how the example is classified.
If we multiply that with the corresponding label,
we get a positive value when the prediction
agrees with the label.
OK?
So we can call this argument agreement.
Let's denote it by z.
Now, we also know that if the point lies exactly
on the margin boundary, say, for a positively labeled point,
the linear prediction is 1.
The label is 1.
And agreement values exactly 1.
If it lies on the correct side of the margin boundary
but beyond the margin boundaries,
then the value of z, the agreement,
will be greater than 1.
So we can now define the laws of how much this preference
to keep the points outside the margin boundaries
is violated by saying that the loss is 0 if the agreement is
greater than equal to 1 and then start
penalizing, giving our last values
for any example that penetrates into the margin boundaries.
For hinge loss, this penalty is 1
minus z if z here is less than 1.
So this will be a positive value that increases.
As z decreases, the agreement decreases below 1.
Now, the regularization-- we've already
seen that we wish to maximize fine values of theta and theta
0 that increase when the norm of parameter vector of theta,
because that is exactly the distance
that the margin boundaries lie around the decision boundary.
Maximizing that is the same as trying
to minimize the norm of theta--
the same as minimizing the squared norm of theta.
And we can just for prettiness, multiply that
by one half, which will become clear later why we do that.
All right?
So we can regularize the solutions
by trying to penalize large values of the norm of parameter
vector theta-squared.
So now, we have an objective function
that guides our selection of parameter vector
theta and theta 0.
That objective function has the two part.
It has an average loss where each loss term measures
how much that example violates their margin boundary defined
according to the hinge loss that we just discussed.
The other term is the regularization term
that tries to push the margin boundaries further and further
apart.
Now, our objective function how we wish to guide the solution
is a balance between the two.
And we set the balance by defining a new parameter called
regularization parameter that simply
weighs how these two terms should affect our solution.
Regularization parameter here is always greater than 0.
OK?
For large values of lambda--
the regularization parameter-- we will favor large margin
solutions but potentially at a cost of incurring
some further loss as the margin boundaries push
past the examples.
If the regularization parameter is very small,
we favor, really, correctly putting the examples
outside the margin boundaries potentially
at a cost of keeping the margin boundary as closer
to the decision boundary.
Optimal value of theta and theta 0
is obtained by minimizing this objective function.
So we have turned the learning problem
into an optimization problem.
Let's look at now how we can illustrate
how the objective function guides the selection of theta
and theta 0.
Ideally, we would change the values of theta and theta 0,
draw a different decision boundary and adjoining margin
boundaries and evaluate the objective function
and then seeing how the minimum of the objective function
is guided by the points, as well as the regularization
parameter.
To make this illustration easier,
I'm going to instead introduce additional points here and just
evaluate what the loss is that the objective function would
assign to those points.
So here, we have a point that lies exactly
on the margin boundary.
We know then how to evaluate the hinge loss of such a point.
It's positively labeled.
Their value of their linear function is exactly 1.
So the agreement here is 1 times 1 or 1.
And the corresponding hinge loss is exactly 0.
So the points on the margin boundary
and on the correct points that are on the correct side
and beyond margin boundaries incurred no loss at all.
Points that now go into the margin boundaries
do start incurring loss.
To evaluate what that value is, let's start
by evaluating what it would be if the point lied exactly
on the decision boundary.
At the decision boundary, the hinge loss
is the linear prediction times label as the argument.
And in this case, it will be 0.
So it will be 1 minus 0 or 1.
OK?
Now, this loss is a linear function--
how much the point violates their margin boundaries.
So the value is 0 here.
It's 1 as it reaches the design boundary.
So at the loss on this point hinge loss for this point
is then in between, which is exactly one half.
OK?
It will be 1, as it reaches the decision boundary
and larger beyond.
Here, we have a negatively labeled point.
We already discussed points that lie exactly
on the decision boundary incur hinge loss which is exactly 1.
Now, a point that goes beyond the decision
boundary to the wrong side under the decision boundary--
so this negatively labeled point now lies on the positive margin
boundary.
So as we move here, it incurs hinge loss 0.
Here, the hinge loss is 1.
And as we take an equal distance step further
in the wrong direction, we get an hinge loss
for this point, which is exactly 2.
All right, and if we go even further,
it will be greater than 2.
All right, so now, we have seen how the different points
incur loss in the objective function
and, thereby, would guide to minimizing
values of theta and theta 0.
We will talk about the solution more later on in terms
of how the solution changes by changing
the regularization parameter lambda.
So things to know from this lecture
is the general point that the learning problems
are cast as optimization problems
in terms of objective functions that
guide the setting of the parameters
that we are estimating.
The objective functions are decomposed into two parts--
average loss over the training examples and the regularization
that guides the type of solution that we are after--
in our case, how large of a margin
we can achieve for the training parts.
We talked about large margin linear classification,
and how it can be turned into an optimization problem.
To this end, we had to define margin boundaries--
the distance that they lie from the decision boundary.
How this relates to the hinge loss
that we defined over the training examples.
And how the regularization pushes the margin boundary
as it apart.
All of this together define, then, the objective
function that guides how theta and theta 0 are resolved
as the minimizing values.