So in this course, you will see two types of lectures.
Tablet lectures where you will see me writing on the tablet
and hear my voice but not actually see my face.
You will also see live blackboard lectures
given by Professor Barzilay.
And we will alternate different topics given by me
and given by Professor Barzilay.
Now, this course has five units.
Unit number 1 focuses on very basic building block
of machine learning methods called linear classification.
And you will learn a very basic algorithm
for solving that problem that will carry on later on.
And you can use it to solve much more complicated problems
as well.
Now, as an illustration then to understand
how these methods actually apply in practice,
you will also be solving a project.
This is like a mini application, going through motions
that you would have to do if you actually solved
a real application problem.
So the application in this case is predicting whether an Amazon
product review, looking at only the text,
whether the review is positive or negative.
Now, we expect that there is a little bit
of a gap between what we have taught you
and what is precisely required to solve this project.
So we expect you to think through and try to figure out
what type of features to use, to feed
in to the linear classifier, and so on.