All right, let's try to understand
the set of linear classifiers.
In particular, let's take a specific linear classifier.
It divides the space into two halves linearly.
So on one side, the classifier says that all the examples
are positive.
And on the other side, they are labeled negative.
The dividing line here is also called decision boundary.
In 2D, that decision boundary is a line.
If x was a one-dimensional quantity,
the decision boundary would be a point.
In 3D, it would be a plane.
And in higher dimensions, it's called
hyperplane that divides the space into two halves.
We can change the linear decision boundary
here and the linear classifier by moving the line around.
So here's another example of a linear classifier.
And again, the shaded side is positive.
And the unshaded one is negative.
And by drawing these lines in this 2D space,
we get the set of linear classifiers over the plane.
So now we need to parameterize the linear classifiers,
so that we can effectively search for the right one
given the training set.
So let's see how we can index and parameterize
these classifiers.
So let's start with even a more restricted version instead
of linear classifiers through origin.
The only difference here is that that dividing line now
is not arbitrarily placed in this two-dimensional space,
but it has to go through origin.
So for example, that line could look like so.
So the equation for this line would
be the set of all points that satisfy an equation for a line
through origin.
To define that, we need to introduce
two parameters, theta 1 that multiplies x1 coordinate,
and theta 2 that multiplies x2 coordinate.
And that is equal to 0.
So you fix the parameters, theta 1 and theta 2.
That fixes what that line is.
And all the x's here--
x here is a vector--
that satisfy this equation lie along this line.
So this is again the decision boundary.
We can write this in a vector form
by introducing now theta as a vector with two coordinates,
theta 1 and theta 2.
And x here is also a vector with two coordinates, x1 and x2.
So we can just write down the decision boundary as all x such
that the inner product or dot product between theta and x
is equal to zero.
OK, so from this equation, you can
see that the parameter vector of theta
is orthogonal to all the points that
lie on the decision boundary.
So if we take a point here and look
at the vector from the origin, then theta
must be somewhere here along this orthogonal line.
So now, let's look at the theta.x as a linear function.
So this is a linear function.
Parameter vector of theta is fixed.
X varies.
So it's your linear function of x.
It is positive on one side of this line
and negative on the other side.
So let's just pick that this side it is positive.
And on this side, it is negative.
And it's exactly 0 along the decision boundary.
So now we know based on this choice
which direction theta must be.
Theta must be oriented in this direction.
Because if you take any point here
for which the linear function takes a positive value,
and then you look at the vector of that,
then the inner product between that x and theta is positive.
And it's negative for any point here.
So now, we have parametric way of writing the decision
boundaries.
And we know which side is a positive one
and which side is the negative one.
This now allows us to define the set of linear classifiers
through origin.
So let's make that a little bit more precise.
We have a classifier.
Now parameterized by the vector, theta.
So each choice of theta defines one classifier.
You change theta, you get a different classifier.
It's oriented differently.
But it also goes through origin.
So that classifier is now simply the sign of theta dot x--
the labels that it returns is a sign of that linear function
theta dot x.
And in general, theta lives in three-dimensional space,
as would x.
So this is now the set of linear classifiers through origin.
So all the choices of--
you try all the parameter values,
you will look at different classifiers.
And all the classifiers that you can
get by bearing the parameter theta are linear classifiers.
And the whole thing is the set of linear classifiers.
Note that this association between the classifier
and the parameter vector theta is not unique.
There are multiple parameter vectors theta
that defined exactly the same classifier.
But each linear classifier through origin
has at least one--
in fact, many parameter vectors theta
that correspond to the same decision
boundary, same decisions.
So what is that degree of freedom here?
If you look at that linear function,
the classifier only cares about the sign of that.
So however, we multiply the value of theta here,
we will get the same classifier as a result.
So the norm of the parameter vector of theta
is not relevant in terms of the decision boundary.
But we will make use of this degree of freedom later on.
One original point that we can understand
is that the theta dot x is the degree to which we classify
the example positively or negatively.
That degree only changes when we move orthogonally
to the decision boundary.
If we take two points here that are equidistant to the decision
boundary and are on the same side,
they are classified as strongly positively.
If their distance from the boundary changes,
then the degree to which they are classified on that side
changes as well.
Now we can use this and define the set of linear classifiers
without the constraint that they have to go through origin.
The only difference here is that we can now move the boundary--
decision boundary to be anywhere, not just those
that go through origin.
Again, we have an orientation of the boundary
as well as the location.
So the decision boundary here is now written in a vector form
slightly differently.
It's all x, such that theta dot x,
which is now-- that inner product is a scalar.
We add a scalar parameter of theta 0 offset parameter.
And that whole thing equals zero.
This is now the decision boundary.
And it is theta 0 that controls the location
of the boundary, where it is in relation to origin.
And theta here controls the orientation of that boundary.
So again, theta, as a vector, is orthogonal to the decision
boundary here.
So on this side on the boundary, again, theta dot x plus theta 0
is positive.
As every time we are on the same side as where theta points,
than the linear function here gives as a positive value.
It's exactly 0 along the boundary.
And it's negative on the other side.
Now, we can use this to define the set of linear classifiers
without the constraint that it has
to go through origin by defining that classifier now
with two parameters, parameter vector of theta
and that scalar theta 0 offset parameter.
And again, similarly saying that the label that's returned
is just a sign of that linear function,
theta dot x plus theta 0.
You specify the two parameters.
You specify the orientation of the line
and where it's located.
And we know which side is positive
and which side is negative.
So theta and theta 0 fully specify the classifier.
Again, the mapping is not unique.
There are many theta and theta 0 that define the same decision
boundary.
But its classifier has now a set of parameters that correspond
to the same decision boundary.
And this whole set of such classifiers,
is then obtained by varying theta as a vector in general
in R d and theta 0 as a scalar parameter.
So this is now the set of linear classifiers.
So when we look for linear classifier,
we try to find parameters theta and theta
0 on the basis of the training set.
And we want to select those class parameters in such a way
that the classifier makes correct decisions.
So to understand this a little bit more,
let's look at whether--
in the figure that I drew, whether the theta
0 scalar parameter here is positive or negative.
So what is that value?
We can just figure it out from this
if we take that linear function, we put origin in place of x.
So we have theta dot, now a zero vector, plus theta 0.
And we see from the figure that this origin
lies on the negative side.
So this has to be negative, which implies,
since this is now 0, that theta 0 itself is negative.
If we move this boundary in this direction past the origin,
theta 0 would become positive.
That is the set of linear classifiers through origin
earlier and now the full set of linear classifiers.